

Summary_

I currently work providing statistical advice and conducting analytics for Stats NZ and Ngāi Tahu (a large South Island iwi). I have extensive experience working on a range of survey and administrative datasets, mainly using a large data warehouse of Government data called the Integrated Data Infrastructure (IDI). In the last two years I have also been learning and applying Bayesian techniques. I have worked on a range of projects from producing statistics at low levels using multi-level Bayesian models, and developing imputation methods for New Zealands new poverty statistics.

Alongside my work, I also study a PhD part-time. In my academic work I conduct research using a range of longitudinal datasets and national surveys. This has lead to a significant increase in my exposure to structural equation models and multi-level modelling, with a number of publications currently in review or preparation.

Employment_____

Te Runanga o Ngai Tahu Statistician	2018 - Present
Statistics New Zealand Statistical Analyst	2016 - Present
University of Otago Senior Research Assistant	2013 - 2016
Queensland Department of Natural Resources and Mines PROJECT OFFICER	2013 - 2015
University of Otago RESEARCH ASSISTANT	2012 - 2014

Education

Victoria University of Wellington	Wellington
DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY	Present
University of Otago	Dunedin
MASTER OF SCIENCE	2016

Awards and scholarships _____

2018	IPANZ Young Professional Of The Year (Top 3)	Institute of Public
	IFAINZ TOUTING FTOTESSIONAL OF THE TEAT (TOP 3)	Administration NZ
2010	Victoria Dantaval Calcalavahia (Differed)	Victoria University
2018 Vid	Victoria Doctoral Scholarship (Differed)	of Wellington
2015	Otago Research Master's Scholarship	University of Otago

Publications

- 1. Riordan, B, T Winter, J Flett, and DSPJ ans T. Conner (In Review). Does the Fear of Missing Out (FoMO) moderate the relationship between social networking use and affect? A daily diary study. *Computers in Human Behavior*.
- 2. Winter, T, T Conner, and P Jose (In Review). Identifying Profiles of Affective Change: An Ecological Momentary Assessment of Flourishers. *Emotion*.

- 3. Winter, T, B Riordan, and A Surace (2019). The relationship between hazardous alcohol use and discrimination among Māori in Aotearoa New Zealand. *Addiction*.
- 4. Surace, A, B Riordan, and T Winter (2019). Do New Zealand sexual minorities engage in more hazardous drinking than non-sexual minorities? *Drug and Alcohol Review*.
- 5. Pittar, N, T Winter, L Falland-Cheung, D Tong, and J Waddell (2018). Scalp simulation A novel approach to site-specific biomechanical modeling of the skin. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials* **77**, 308–313.
- 6. Falland-Cheung, L, JN Waddell, MS Lazarjan, MC Jermy, T Winter, D Tong, and PA Brunton (2017). Use of agar/glycerol and agar/glycerol/water as a translucent brain simulant for ballistic testing. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials* **65**, 665–671.
- 7. Franz, EA, Y Fu, M Moore, T Winter, T Mayne, R Debnath, and C Stringer (2016). Fooling the brain by mirroring the hand: brain correlates of the perceptual capture of limb ownership. *Restorative neurology and neuroscience* **34**(5), 721–732.
- 8. Tong, D, T Winter, J Jin, A Bennett, and J Waddell (2015). Quantification of subconcussive impact forces to the head using a forensic model. *Journal of Clinical Neuroscience* **22**(4), 747–751.
- 9. Winter, TJ and EA Franz (2014). Implication of the anterior commissure in the allocation of attention to action. *Frontiers in Psychology* **5**.

Presentations and posters

Using overseas surveys to produce reliable models of sexual minorities 2019 New Zealand Population Conference, Wellington Alcohol use disparities among gender and sexual minorities in New Zealand (Poster) 2019 COLLABORATIVE PERSPECTIVES ON ADDICTION, RHODE ISLAND Iwi data tool using integrated data and R Shiny 2017 IWI DATA CONFERENCE, CHRISTCHURCH Using data to support a collective impact model of Maori potential 2016 POPULATION ASSOCIATION OF NEW ZEALAND CONFERENCE, CHRISTCHURCH The effect of motherhood on income 2016 NEW ZEALAND ASSOCIATION OF ECONOMISTS CONFERENCE, WELLINGTON A machine learning approach to classifying life course outcomes 2016 LONGITUDINAL AND MULTIVARIATE ANALYSIS NETWORK (STATS NZ), WELLINGTON Methodology for comparing incomes between parents and non-parents 2016 STATISTICAL METHODS SEIMINAR (STATS NZ), WELLINGTON Inter-hemispheric inhibition in the autistic brain 2014 NEUROETHICS SEMINAR, DUNEDIN

Skills

- · Languages such as SQL, R, Python, SAS, SPSS Syntax, Bash
- Structural equation modelling and causal analysis
- Bayesian statistics, using brms in R (Stan backend)
- Machine learning techniques such as random forests and neural nets
- Strong background using big data, i.e. the Integrated Data Infrastructure (IDI) at Stats NZ
- Knowledge of Tikanga Māori

Referees

Available on request